export const quiz = [
  {
    id: 1,
    question: "What is the purpose of `useState` in React?",
    answer: "To manage state in a functional component",
    show: false,
  },
  {
    id: 2,
    question: "What method is used to update state in a class component?",
    answer: "setState",
    show: false,
  },
  {
    id: 3,
    question:
      "Which lifecycle method is called after a component is rendered for the first time?",
    answer: "componentDidMount",
    show: false,
  },
  {
    id: 4,
    question: "What hook is used for side effects in functional components?",
    answer: "useEffect",
    show: false,
  },
  {
    id: 5,
    question: "What is JSX?",
    answer: "A syntax extension that looks similar to XML",
    show: false,
  },
  {
    id: 6,
    question: "What does the `key` prop do in React?",
    answer: "Helps React identify which items have changed",
    show: false,
  },
  {
    id: 7,
    question: "How do you pass data to child components?",
    answer: "Via props",
    show: false,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question: "What is the purpose of `useContext` in React?",
    answer: "To access context values in functional components",
    show: false,
  },
  {
    id: 9,
    question: "What does `React.memo` do?",
    answer: "Memoizes a component to prevent unnecessary re-renders",
    show: false,
  },
  {
    id: 10,
    question: "What is the default value of a controlled input in React?",
    answer: "An empty string or an appropriate initial value",
    show: false,
  },
  {
    id: 11,
    question:
      "What is the purpose of the `componentDidUpdate` lifecycle method?",
    answer: "To perform actions after component updates",
    show: false,
  },
  {
    id: 12,
    question:
      "What hook would you use to create a stateful value that persists across renders but doesn't trigger a re-render when it changes?",
    answer: "useRef",
    show: false,
  },
  {
    id: 13,
    question:
      "What is the correct way to bind event handlers in class components?",
    answer: "Using the constructor or arrow functions",
    show: false,
  },
  {
    id: 14,
    question: "What does `React.createElement` do?",
    answer: "Creates a new React element",
    show: false,
  },
  {
    id: 15,
    question: "What is a PureComponent in React?",
    answer: "A component that only re-renders if its props or state change",
    show: false,
  },
];
